I do think that the the more comments
I'm seeing are showing disbelief. I
think that's the general feeling I'm
getting. Reading the comments seems to
indicate that the majority of people out
there seem to be more pessimistic, more
bearish. In other words, there's
disbelief out there. It was there's been
a lot of pessimism towards Bitcoin this
year is healthy for the continuation
overall uh for Bitcoin to go higher. You
had negative sentiment. You've got
bullish divergences into key levels.
That's about all you need. There are
fundamental reasons why it could go a
lot higher over the over the longer
term.
>> If Bitcoin at some point in the next few
months goes to 100K and above 100K, I'll
guarantee there'll be people out there
saying, "Oh, 500K, it's obvious."
Charlie, it's really interesting what
we're seeing on Bitcoin. Uh just
recently, Bitcoin managed to take out
resistance at the levels at the spring
highs and the May highs. uh which by the
way triggered the Dow theory bullish
signal. So my good friend and trader
Manuel Bllye he's essentially saying
look uh Bitcoin has bottomed and in his
view according to the Dow theory model
um he believes that we're now in a bull
market and I have to say that there are
other indications as well which seems to
um corroborate that view that
potentially Bitcoin has bottomed and
that uh we could perhaps see an uptrend
developing despite any pullbacks or
corrections that may occur. Uh, and I'll
get your view on this, uh, Charlie
because I'm interested to hear whether
you agree with this view or not. Uh, but
before before I go on, I should say that
I recently posted a video on Bitcoin.
And I noticed that the the ratio of
pessimistic versus optimistic comments
are about even, but it seems that not
everybody is bullish. So, it seems to be
that uh, from the comments I've been
reading, I would say about half are
pessimistic or bearish. they're
expecting Bitcoin to retest the lows it
formed uh back at near 57K or 60K. Now,
the other half are saying, well, of
course it's a bottom. Well, of course,
it's going to go to new all-time highs.
It's like it's almost obvious. Well, um
so they're they're more leaning towards
bullish. Uh so, the sentiment I would
say right now is mixed. I do think that
the the more comments I'm seeing are
showing disbelief. I think that's the
general feeling I'm getting. Reading the
comments seems to indicate that the
majority of people out there in the
Bitcoin community or watching these
videos seem to be more pessimistic, more
bearish. In other words, there's
disbelief out there. So, that's that's
what I'm getting. That's the impression
I'm getting. And by the way, guys, the
reason why sentiment is so important is
because it's really important to know
what the crowd is thinking because the
crowd again bird mentality is often a
good contrarian signal. A great book on
this I'm reading right now. Oh, it's by
the way I just started reading this is
the crowd by Gustav Leon uh written
1890s. Okay. So really good book. Get
that and check it out. Yeah. So crowd
psychology really important here. What
are you seeing U Charlie before we go
and talk about Bitcoin? What do you
think about the sentiment right now
about Bitcoin at the moment relative to
what it was some months ago perhaps?
>> Well I think I was just about to say
well for the year overall um but
generally speaking this year that I've
yeah my measures of sentiment as well.
Um it was there's been a lot of
pessimism towards Bitcoin this year and
other and crypto in general. Um and so
um I mean when Bitcoin came down to 50
odd,000
how many people were looking for it to
come to 30 or 40,000 you know or even
lower.
>> I got to say I'm guilty of that too
because uh when when it dropped down to
the lows sorry to interrupt you by the
way.
>> That's right. Yeah. But uh certainly
when it dropped down to 60K, some of the
technicals and the Dow theory model,
they're they're essentially showing that
the bare market could continue to 50K.
But I I will say this, I I also saw
divergences, positive divergences, which
are leaning more towards bullish.
Bitcoin has made a lower low here as we
can see on the daily chart. But with a
higher low on the MACD, a divergence, a
positive divergence, we would then need
to see an impulsive rally. In other
words, in order to indicate or increase
the probability of a bottom, whether
intermediate or long-term, we would have
to see a break again, an impulsive rally
or break above these levels of
resistance at 67,264
to 70,512.
I began to change my mind to towards a
rally. So, I should just say guys that
in the video I posted back in August,
the August 20th member video, I actually
mentioned that Bitcoin could see a rally
back up to 77K and even 82K based on the
trend line break. So, when the trend
line broke, Bitcoin has managed to break
out, break this trend line. So, by
breaking this resistance region again,
the 200 SMA, keeping it simple, as long
as Bitcoin can remain above support,
there's potential here for bulls to
extend this further higher. In other
words, for the potential and the
probability for a move into the 1382 and
the 161 at golden ratio extension. So
that remains the higher probability
here. And by the way, if this region
also breaks, there's also potential for
a move eventually to test this region as
well between the 38.2% level here at
83,700 to about 80,600 to retest that
major resistance high. So that potential
was there. However, one thing I wasn't
sure about and still again, nobody can
be sure. Nobody can be certain. But one
thing we can obviously never be certain
of is whether the rally is corrective,
you know, you know, just a correction
before it drops down again or whether
the rally is the start of a new uptrend.
And that's actually something we want to
talk about. I want to talk about with
you in this video.
>> So yeah, uh I think we had a backdrop of
pessimism. And you're right, you can't
time pessimism. You have to then couple
that with the technicals as well and
other and other information. But um but
certainly we had the backdrop there. A
lot of pessimists out there this year
and it's interesting you said that it's
mixed even from your comments in your
videos at the moment. So I think that's
healthy in that is healthy for the
continuation overall uh for Bitcoin to
go higher. For me technically um it did
those divergences. That was the thing on
the weekly charts. I'm sure you'll show
that there was a big weekly divergence
there. So, I I got bullish once we did
the double bottom. That's when I uh got
bullish. And also at that very point,
you know, I'm a moving average person.
We came into the monthly 50 period
moving average. I think it was a trend
line on your chart as well. And um so it
was it was a nice you had negative
sentiment. You've got bullish
divergences into key levels. That's
about all you need. I did notice a
divergence on the weekly chart. I
totally agree with you. As a matter of
fact, we're getting another divergence
with respect to the February low. So, we
can see that we're getting another
positive divergence here as well. As a
matter of fact, it's much more clear on
the weekly time frame. The MACD on the
weekly time frame is also showing a
positive divergence. I was waiting for a
break of resistance like a trend line
resistance which I mentioned back in
August before I can be more confident
about a bottom or in other words about a
temporary intermediate bottom and then a
rally.
>> Uh my question is do you wait for a
break of resistance just to confirm or
increase the probability of that
divergence? You don't.
>> No, I'm an aggressive trader. Okay.
>> Um I do need something you know that
divergence is a specific pattern that I
trade. So I have specific rules and
entry rules around that. So, I don't
need to wait for a trend line break in
that in that situation because I have
other rules of I only need a a half
decent uh up closing bar on that given
time frame to then give the the signal
for me. So, I don't need to wait that
long.
>> You said you're more of an aggressive
trader. So, it's more aggressive.
>> Yeah, you trade more aggressively. So
does that mean that when you see a
divergence, you put a stop loss in place
and essentially you go with the
divergence like let's say if it's an if
it's a bullish divergence it's a
positive divergence then you get long
with a wide stop loss and then either
hit your stop in which case you're
stopped out for for a small loss
>> or you um
>> or I get a great riskreward. I mean
Bitcoin is different to me anyway. I
don't I don't trade Bitcoin. Um trading
is using stops and all of that. I'm just
a long-term investor in it. So, you
know, unleveraged and all of that, but
you can still take the same patterns
>> and and have a cut off. Yes. If you
because there's plenty of people out
there who are trading it. And so, yeah,
I would traditionally be in long before
a trend line gets broken. Um, so I just
need to see a nice strong up bar and
that will be enough for me once the
divergence is in and then the up bar and
I will use that. So it's a bit more
aggressive but it does mean that the
risk-to-reward ratio is strong as well.
>> My other question to you was this
whether you think the balance of
probabilities has now shifted towards a
rally to new all-time highs. Uh or do
you think you know what and I'm I'm
guessing the the answer to your question
to this will be a no. But do you think
there's still high probability of a drop
or a crash back down to the lows of 60k
or 57k? I'm guessing from what you've
told me so far that you're more leaning
towards the bullish side of things,
especially as I just mentioned, a lot of
the sentiment and even among social
media comments that I've been reading
are more well mixed, but they're more
lean towards disbelief or actually the
more pessimistic bearish side which
supports a contrarian view for more
potential upside perhaps in the next
several weeks and months.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I am um on balance and
so um I think that the price action that
we've seen even just recently I think it
all looks very constructive. I'm not
necessarily looking for new alltime
highs this year. Maybe not even next
year. Um so but I'm certainly bullish
towards it overall. Um I just not
entirely sure that we're going to be
going to new alltime highs in the next
few months. You know that sort of thing.
So, I am bullish on it, but um you know,
and it'll move around, of course, it'll
have little pullbacks and stuff, but I
my contention is that the low that we
put in uh a few months ago into a major
lows on high time frames with a a flush
in negative sentiment
should be a major low.
>> Yeah. As a matter of fact, this is
something I mentioned in my videos
before, which is the drop that occurred
uh back in the summer. As a matter of
fact, reached a trend line, which we
looked at by the way, major trend line,
uptrend line, support, held it, bounced,
and moved back above the 200 weekly
average, which again were signs, strong
signs of positivity, a potential
bullishness, uh, of a potential rally.
Of course, one thing we didn't know at
the time and we still don't know, I
mean, there's still uncertainty out
there and markets are chaotic and
unpredictable. One thing we didn't know
and we still don't know is whether this
rally that we're seeing right now, the
rally we've seen so far from the summer
lows near 60k or 57k, whether this is
start of an uptrend taking us to new
all-time highs or whether it's just a
correction, temporary correction which
could still go higher but and then
eventually drop down to continue the
bare market. That's something we don't
know and it's again nobody knows. It's
impossible to know with 100% certainty,
but it seems the probabilities are
leaning towards at least some kind of a
bottom, intermediate or long-term, and
then the potential for a new bull
market, an uptrend. Whether the uptrend
or bull market will take us will take us
to new all-time highs. That is the
unknown. Perhaps enough information is
not out there for us to determine that.
But you're you're at least saying, look,
even if we don't go to all-time highs
this year or even next year, there is
scope for a rally of some sort taking us
higher. Is that
>> Yeah, I think I think um well, well,
it's twofold. One is I think that low,
>> you know, I think that was a material
low. It was a good technical low on high
time frames coupled with, you know, mass
pessimism out there. I think it's just
ideal as a low. The hardest thing is to
know is to predict and I'm not in the
prediction business but you know that oh
it's going to go to you know 150,000 or
200,000 and when but I can be bullish
overall. Um I'm not convinced
the timing of when it goes back up if it
is going to get there to those prior
highs. That's the hardest thing. But I
think there's enough scope in it to uh
still have a nice run even if it doesn't
go straight back to 120, you know. So,
yeah, I I mean, you know, I'm bullish on
it. Yeah.
>> But I one thing that I can't say to you,
sorry. Um is loads of people out there
saying it's going to go to 500,000 or
million or whatever.
>> That's why I'm not in that business.
>> Just give it enough, Charlie. Just give
it time. I I'll guarantee you as soon as
Bitcoin if Bitcoin at some point in the
next few months goes to 100K and above
100K I'll guarantee there'll be people
out there saying oh 500k it's obvious
you know those people will suddenly come
out of the woods
>> had the same in silver at the beginning
of this year I had all of that on my
channel at the beginning of the year
people say oh silver's Charlie you're
wrong silver's going to 500 okay
when are they coming back to to wrap you
up in that in that special suit
>> that's True. That's true.
>> So, um I don't actually I don't want to
>> I'm joking. Uh but because anything can
happen in the markets, but um but
generally speaking, you know, there are
certain levels in markets that
>> uh that uh are very likely not going to
go straight to silver going to 500 or or
whatever. But uh Bitcoin, who knows?
Yeah, there there is there are
fundamental reasons why it could go a
lot higher over the over the longer
term. the timing of that I find a bit
more difficult. So, for now, I'll remain
bullish and I'll just see as and when it
as and when it can get back to those
100%. Can I just let you know that
Charlie and I are doing a joint
educational course on trading and
technical analysis in November. That's
on Sunday, November 8th. Full details
are here on this link you see here, Pro
Trading Workshop. And you get a
discount, a major discount when you go
and sign up today. By the way guys, just
let you know, we got a lot of tremendous
feedback when we did this course uh back
in January of uh this year. So, I'll
just read you some of the comments I
received. Uh this one says uh from
Robert B. Uh condensed and valuep
packed. I'm already re-watching the
recordings and applying the techniques.
The workshop was worth every penny. Uh
thanks, Robert. This one is from Ryan L.
Great insights that have improved my
trading. No end. From January to now, my
win rate and more importantly,
profitability has grown a big amount.
And then uh from Boris who says well
structured and informative it gave me
more guidelines of how to in trade
invest and I'm looking forward to the
next one. Charlie if you can just tell
everyone briefly about what's involved.
Again I'll be covering u the technical
analysis side of this particular course
and Charlie if you could just give a
brief outline. Yeah, it's um probably
about seven hours of tuition, both
yourself and myself sharing our probably
a bit more of our intimate elements of
how we go about trading, your analysis,
how you pull all that together in order
to make your informed decisions and I
talk more on a strategy basis, specific
mechanical strategy, entry techniques,
exit techniques, all of that sort of
stuff. I'll be showing a full, you know,
two full strategies as well in the
course of that. So, it's quite intense.
Um, that's why we're recording it
because it's a lot to take in. Um, and
like you just said, we had great
feedback in January. So, u, and there
were people that have said, "Oh, could
you do it again?" So, we're doing it
again Sunday the 8th.
>> Brilliant. Thanks very much, Charlie.
And guys, remember the discount, the
early bird discount is right there for
you in go link protradingworkshop.com.
Uh the link is in the description and
full details about the course uh are
also on that link. See you guys in
November. Thanks so much Charlie. Much
appreciate